<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//IXIA//DTD IXIA DITA Composite//EN" "../../system/dtd/ixia/IxiaDitabase.dtd">
<reference id="blackberry_push_PushService_createChannel" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title><apiname>createChannel</apiname></title>
    <shortdesc><i>Creates a push channel for the given application. Once a channel is created, it will survive application restarts and therefore does not necessarily need to be called on every application start up. However, for a consumer application, since it is possible for the public/BIS PPG to destroy a channel under certain circumstances it may be advisable to periodicially re-create the channel (e.g. once a month). A successful <code>create</code> must have been done before calling this function. This function should be called in order for an application to be able to start receiving pushes. If a <code>destroyChannel</code> call is then made, no pushes will be able to be received until a <code>createChannel</code> call is made again.</i></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <title>Synopsis:</title>
                <pre scale="80">createChannel = function(createChannelCallback){}</pre>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Parameters:</title>
            <dl>
                <dlentry>
                    <dt><varname>createChannelCallback</varname> {Function}</dt>
                    <dd><p>The callback that is invoked when the result of the create channel operation is received.</p>
                        <dl>
                            <dlentry>
                                <dt><varname>result</varname> {Number}</dt>
                                <dd><p>The create channel operation result. See the constants provided to see what result codes apply for this operation.</p></dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry>
                                <dt><varname>token</varname> {String}</dt>
                                <dd><p>On a successful create channel operation (result of<code>SUCCESS</code>), a token is returned. This token must then be communicated back to the content provider's server-side application (the Push Initiator). This token is then used by the content provider as the means to address the application on the device when initiating a push request to the PPG.</p></dd>
                            </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
            </dl>
        </section>
        <example>
            <title>Example:</title>
            <p><pre scale="80">
                &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;

pushService.createChannel(createChannelCallback);

function createChannelCallback(result, token) {
    if (result === blackberry.push.PushService.SUCCESS) {
        // Success, so a token should be available
        // Subscribe with the Push Initiator using this
        // token (if your Push Initiator supports subscription)
        // so that you can push to this user using this token
    } else if (result ===
        blackberry.push.PushService.INTERNAL_ERROR) {
        // Retry the createChannel up to a certain number of
        // attempts and then display an error to the user
    } else if ... (handle all the error codes possible for
                   createChannel - see the error constants
                   in this PushService class)
}

                &lt;/script&gt;
            </pre></p>
        </example>
    </refbody>
</reference>
